<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>A strange place</title><id>https://voidhymns.space/feed.xml</id><subtitle>Recent Posts</subtitle><updated>2025-03-24T23:37:58Z</updated><link href="https://voidhymns.space/feed.xml" rel="self" /><link href="https://voidhymns.space" /><entry><title>The Necromancer and the Witch</title><id>https://voidhymns.space/the-necromancer-and-the-witch.html</id><author><name></name><email></email></author><updated>2025-02-16T20:42:00Z</updated><link href="https://voidhymns.space/the-necromancer-and-the-witch.html" rel="alternate" /><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;The Necromancer and the Witch&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you know what you're doing, the Forest was actually one of the safer places in the world. Felix, of course, did know what she was doing. Knowing one is safe and actually feeling safe are two very different experiences though. She heard the soft giggle of ringing bells in a patch of fog a ways away to her left, and saw dancing illumination within that patch, beckoning her to join in the fun.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Felix closed her eyes and took a deep, calming breath, reflexively fidgeting with the ring she wore to protect herself from the unknown. One of her many mentors had given her that ring to help her navigate the Forest safely, so that she may visit. After a few moments of breathwork, her heart rate began to slow to a normal rhythm, and she set her walking pace to match the beat. Matching rhythms was good, helped her ignore the flying objects which sped above the canopy, and to put the gaze of the trees out of mind.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every nation she'd ever visited seemed to have some Forest of its own, always presenting differently. Sometimes it was a dark, forgotten city of unfathomable creatures. Sometimes it was an island of mysteries which would beckon you to explore and lose yourself. Sometimes it was a hidden corner within networked computers where things humanity tried to cover up waited in resentment and glee. This particular Forest was very... traditionally fariy tale. The perfect place for Felix's friend and mentor to live.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She hadn't noticed exactly when she arrived in front of the cottege. It was entirely possible that the place only appeared when one was not paying attention after all. How thematically fitting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Vines covered the cottege and only occassionally showed a peek of the cobblestone and wooden walls beneith the folage. A small path creeped through the front garden of all types of herbs and flowers. Looking at the roof, Felix could see the tree the cottege was constructed around and the autumnial leaves that grew from the branches. She smiled a bit, noting that outside the Forest and in the region with the Machine, the season was closer to spring. What a deliberate choice of season. On one side of the roof was the chimny, gently exhaling the tell-tale smoke of a cozy fire within the hearth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The door opened, and from it stepped one of her ~~girls~~ dolls, who politely greeted Felix with a bow. &amp;quot;Please, come inside and relax. Miss has been looking forward to your visit&amp;quot;, it said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Are you still scared that I'll try something?&amp;quot; said the witch, startling Felix out of the slight daze.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Ah! No ma'am!&amp;quot; Felix said quickly, a bit embarassed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The room was warm and comfortable, and she had been staring into the cup of coffee that one of the dolls had placed before her. Tea was the typical drink served, but Felix was more of a coffee girl. She had been thinking about the first time she had met her friend and mentor, the witch called Potentia. Back then, she had only started coming to the understand the nature of this world, and found herself outside the cottege, and then inside, and then stairing at a cup of tea across from the witch. Felix had heard rumors, gaze going back and forth between the witch, the tea, and the doll who had served it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The witch had laughed, and said &amp;quot;Oh no my dear, that wouldn't work on you. You're already so much You.&amp;quot; Then, to reassure her guest, the witch took a sip from both cups. Somewhat reassured, Felix took a sip, coughed, and asked if there was any coffee. Or an energy drink.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Felix focused on the figure across the table from her, now firmly back in the present.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;The coffee's great, ma'am! Thank you for keeping it around for me!&amp;quot; she said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Wonderful! Now dear, what is the occassion that brings you to my home? It's been some time, after all.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Felix smiled, feeling the excitement and pride of her work flare up and shining within her chest. She had been waiting a long time to say what she what she was about to.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;It worked! Your teachings, your way of creating Masks? I did it!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Felix looked at her mentor. Potentia typically had a calm and collected exterior, face always locked into a vistage which projected a wisdom and insight that was always just slightly out of reach for the ones gazing upon her. But Felix knew where to look. She looked at her eyes, at the slight change in how she held her hands, and Felix knew that the witch was positively beaming inside. Noticing that propelled Felix's good mood even further.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Tell me everything,&amp;quot; Potentia requested, setting her cup down gently upon the saucer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Yes ma'am!&amp;quot; said said, taking a deep breath before launching into her infodump.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;It worked a lot like how you showed me, with imbuing the traits upon the Mask construct using the steps in the books you outlined which was a great first step and I was able to use that to teach the others how to make their own masks and then we started testing out the limits so I tried to develop a few but they kept getting Contradicted and they fell off but my friends didn't have that problem and I wasn't sure because they could take them on and off and on and off without any issue but I couldn't experiment any further because like hell am I gonna try putting a Mask onto someone without their consent but putting it on other things wasn't working so then we were hanging out in the Forest and one of the Shy Folk came over and it just struck me that maybe I could try it on that by making one of the properties something like 'I exist therefore I can be interacted with' and I reached across and was actually able to give her the Mask and she put it on and turned into a ghost and it was so cool and I think it's reproducable but I need help and-&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;That's wonderful!&amp;quot; said Potentia, &amp;quot;Does your doll have a name?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The question was a dagger to Felix's good mood: punctured and instantly deflated. A &lt;em&gt;doll&lt;/em&gt;? One of the &lt;em&gt;things&lt;/em&gt; that the witch turned people into? That was a weighty accusation. Kinda pissed her off, actually.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;em&gt;Her&lt;/em&gt; name is Kit. And she's not a doll. She's a ghost and she's very much her own being.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Oh. Oh yes, of course. I'm sorry, dear. I just thought...&amp;quot; the witch trailed off, unsure what to say next.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They sat together in the awkward silence, with only the sound of the fire crackling and the dolls within the cottege completing their tasks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;future notes redacted&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Bill's shenanigans, pt 1</title><id>https://voidhymns.space/bills-shenanigans-pt-1.html</id><author><name></name><email></email></author><updated>2025-02-14T23:34:00Z</updated><link href="https://voidhymns.space/bills-shenanigans-pt-1.html" rel="alternate" /><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;WORK IN PROGRESS&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Running a universe was easy, actually. All one had to do was take the current state of things, destroy the entire universe, and then recreate it again exactly one moment later. This process needed to happen at every moment throughout all of history and into the future, for every single possible timeline in the synaptic net of causality. For efficiency, Bill elected to divide the work by dividing herself into very large number of copies of herself, so that each moment could happen in lock step. Every situation and moment had a copy of her standing there, ready to destroy and repaint the universe into existence link an assembly line. Bill was very good at her job.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just because it is simple to run a universe, does not mean it is a rapid process. Though the little ones living on stage in the universe never experienced the eons between transitions, Bill and her siblings ended up quite a lot of, well, time on their hands in between those snapshots. A mortal might ponder the situation with growing horror at the prospect, fearing being overcome with isolation and boredom in the abyss of time between times, without realizing that such fearful experiences are exclusively for the little ones within the universe. It is difficult to become bored when one is experiencing all of time and space at the same time. Plus, an angel's biology simply did not come equipped to experience boredom or horror or dread; that was their dad's job.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also she had hobbies, thank you very much. Bill loved nothing more than to peak into the universe and watch the little ones playing life. And she would get hyper fixated on those stories, and start seeing herself in them, and then finally decided to start cosplaying as that particular one. So far, she had several trillion cosplays, and was always keeping an eye out for when inspiration struck next. What could she say, she got it from her dad. Sometimes she would pluck a little one out of the universe for a brief chat, asking &amp;quot;Hey, why'd you make that decision?&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;I'm writing a fic about you, what would you order at a cafe in a coffee shop AU? Also it's enemies to lovers.&amp;quot; They never really understood the artistic vision, and mostly just screamed till she put them back in.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bill swam through the network of causality. Mortals often thought of time and timelines as an endlessly divergent set of lines, never to meet again. That was silly; moving left one step and then right one step had the same end state as moving right one step and then left. Situations re-converge more often than most mortals imagined. No, it was better to see causality and timelines as a set of lines which connect each moment together, and would activate a moment when enough causality went into them. From Bill's perspective, it was plain to see that cause is to effect as dendrite is to axion. Time and situations activating and propagating along a network, with new connections being made by her sister. Some events never take place, and those ties eventually wither away. Other events take place so often that it is certain fate to go down a particular path if events ever lead there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She occasionally wondered what the network of cause and effect was thinking. Sometimes she wondered if she was looking at the mind of her father. Sometimes she wondered if she was looking at the mind of something else they were trying to make. It doesn't matter either way, really.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Certain clusters in the network were really interesting. It felt like anything could happen in them. She flew over to one such cluster, and nearly ran into one of the most powerful beings in the entire universe. The first god (after Bill's father, of course), a primordial force capable of ripping apart reality and stitching it back together in what ever shape She desired. She had countless names, uttered by mortals scattered throughout all of creation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With all due reverence, Bill began the appropriate rites for greeting Her. She ran and tackle hugged Her to the ground, with a glomp, shouting &amp;quot;Aunt Shepherd!!!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry></feed>