<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>A strange place</title><id>https://voidhymns.space/feeds/tags/bill.xml</id><subtitle>Tag: bill</subtitle><updated>2025-03-24T23:37:58Z</updated><link href="https://voidhymns.space/feeds/tags/bill.xml" rel="self" /><link href="https://voidhymns.space" /><entry><title>Bill's shenanigans, pt 1</title><id>https://voidhymns.space/bills-shenanigans-pt-1.html</id><author><name></name><email></email></author><updated>2025-02-14T23:34:00Z</updated><link href="https://voidhymns.space/bills-shenanigans-pt-1.html" rel="alternate" /><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;WORK IN PROGRESS&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Running a universe was easy, actually. All one had to do was take the current state of things, destroy the entire universe, and then recreate it again exactly one moment later. This process needed to happen at every moment throughout all of history and into the future, for every single possible timeline in the synaptic net of causality. For efficiency, Bill elected to divide the work by dividing herself into very large number of copies of herself, so that each moment could happen in lock step. Every situation and moment had a copy of her standing there, ready to destroy and repaint the universe into existence link an assembly line. Bill was very good at her job.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just because it is simple to run a universe, does not mean it is a rapid process. Though the little ones living on stage in the universe never experienced the eons between transitions, Bill and her siblings ended up quite a lot of, well, time on their hands in between those snapshots. A mortal might ponder the situation with growing horror at the prospect, fearing being overcome with isolation and boredom in the abyss of time between times, without realizing that such fearful experiences are exclusively for the little ones within the universe. It is difficult to become bored when one is experiencing all of time and space at the same time. Plus, an angel's biology simply did not come equipped to experience boredom or horror or dread; that was their dad's job.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also she had hobbies, thank you very much. Bill loved nothing more than to peak into the universe and watch the little ones playing life. And she would get hyper fixated on those stories, and start seeing herself in them, and then finally decided to start cosplaying as that particular one. So far, she had several trillion cosplays, and was always keeping an eye out for when inspiration struck next. What could she say, she got it from her dad. Sometimes she would pluck a little one out of the universe for a brief chat, asking &amp;quot;Hey, why'd you make that decision?&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;I'm writing a fic about you, what would you order at a cafe in a coffee shop AU? Also it's enemies to lovers.&amp;quot; They never really understood the artistic vision, and mostly just screamed till she put them back in.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bill swam through the network of causality. Mortals often thought of time and timelines as an endlessly divergent set of lines, never to meet again. That was silly; moving left one step and then right one step had the same end state as moving right one step and then left. Situations re-converge more often than most mortals imagined. No, it was better to see causality and timelines as a set of lines which connect each moment together, and would activate a moment when enough causality went into them. From Bill's perspective, it was plain to see that cause is to effect as dendrite is to axion. Time and situations activating and propagating along a network, with new connections being made by her sister. Some events never take place, and those ties eventually wither away. Other events take place so often that it is certain fate to go down a particular path if events ever lead there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She occasionally wondered what the network of cause and effect was thinking. Sometimes she wondered if she was looking at the mind of her father. Sometimes she wondered if she was looking at the mind of something else they were trying to make. It doesn't matter either way, really.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Certain clusters in the network were really interesting. It felt like anything could happen in them. She flew over to one such cluster, and nearly ran into one of the most powerful beings in the entire universe. The first god (after Bill's father, of course), a primordial force capable of ripping apart reality and stitching it back together in what ever shape She desired. She had countless names, uttered by mortals scattered throughout all of creation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With all due reverence, Bill began the appropriate rites for greeting Her. She ran and tackle hugged Her to the ground, with a glomp, shouting &amp;quot;Aunt Shepherd!!!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry></feed>